

Davis (Peng-Chou) Chen

Software Developer / UX Engineer

🏡 From Taiwan. Based in Indianapolis, Indiana.

Website

LinkedIn Profile

Summary

Currently my focus area is front-end development with Angular, but I am also skilled in UX design and engineering. Had working experiences as a software engineer in Ethernet switch firmware and IP-based application development. Open-minded, straightforward and excellent problem solving ability to perform well and enthusiastically in a team.

Work Experience

Software Developer at TCC Software Solutions

Indianapolis, Indiana USA | Nov 2019-present

- Designed and developed RESTful style web applications and functional dashboards for licensing agent clients
- Maintain and enhance existing web applications and all integrated systems utilizing C#, ASP.NET, Javascript, JSON, AJAX and jQuery
- Maintain existing database-driven web interfaces for data communication using SQL Server 2012

Product Design Intern at Delta Electronics 台達電子

Taipei, Taiwan | Jul 2018-Aug 2018

 Collaborated with developers and project leads to provide intuitive user experiences for digital web-based tools

- Delivered analysis and insights from research on note-taking tools and project management tools along with product owner and team players.
- Created wireframe, storyboard, and interactive prototypes for web and mobile apps
- Translated requirements into interaction diagrams and transformed them into consistent and intuitive UI
- Hosted a design workshop providing creative and innovative product designs, and shared insights and design process actively with the team to increase communication and project effectiveness

Accomplishments

- AirStraw: Designed reusable straws that analyze ingredients and generated the health reports. As the team facilitator and the UX designer, conducted marketing analytics, expert interviews, wireframing, and digital prototyping. The design was the runner up in the 12 internship teams creative competition.
- Digital Workshop Tool: Led the business analysis and the UX design of a digital workshop and meeting hosting application (includes pc and mobile version).

Software Engineer at Volktek Corp. 定揚科技

Taipei, Taiwan | Nov 2013-Dec 2016

- Implemented protocol command line and designed web GUI for management-enabled L2 switches
- Developed embedded firmware for metro Ethernet and industry switches
- Created software documentation, including software features, test reviews, management UI design
- Collaborated with developers and project leads to provide intuitive user experiences for digital web-based tools

Accomplishments

 Cable Test: Implemented cable speed and functionality test feature into company products, and collaborated with the QA team members to create test plan of cable test feature to increase department communication and project effectiveness.

 SNMPv3: led designed and built command line and web GUI of SNMPv3 feature in the products; provided a feature guideline and slides presentation to sales and marketing team.

Education

Master's Degree in Human-Computer Interaction and Design

Indiana University Bloomington

Bloomington, Indiana USA

May 2019

Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science

National Dong Hwa University

Hualien, Taiwan Jun 2012

Skills



Software

- Adobe Creative Cloud
- Figma
- Axure

Research

- Affinity Diagram
- Card Sorting
- Competitive Analysis

Programming

Software

- Visual Studio
- Visual Studio Code
- SQL Server Reporting Services

Web Development

- ASP.NET
- CSS
- HTML

- Contextual Inquiry
- Interviews
- Participatory Design
- Personas
- User Experience Mapping
- User Research
- Workshops

UX Design

- Information Architecture
- Interaction Design
- Prototyping
- Sketching
- Usability Testing
- Wireframing

- Javascript
- PHP
- SQL

Web Frameworks

- AngularJS
- Bootstrap
- JQuery

Others

- Arduino
- Blender
- C & C++
- Git
- Unity